这是什么地方
What is this place?
旧金山
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
我的生活确实过于离谱
My life doesn't really make sense.
♪ Your dreams were your ticket out   你的梦想就是你的出路 ♪
嗨
Hey.
对此我曾经问过自己很多问题
I used to ask myself a lot of questions about that.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
"斯科特  你离过婚  蹲过牢  怎么就成为复仇者了呢"
"Scott, you're a divorced ex-con. How are you an Avenger?
♪ To that same old place that you laughed about   回到老地方  让你捧腹大笑 ♪
"为什么能和美国队长一块儿时空旅行呢"
"Why are you time traveling with Captain America?
♪ Well the names have all changed since you hung around   自从你在我身边名字都变了 ♪
"这也太离谱了"
"That doesn't make sense."
♪ But those dreams have remained   但那些梦想依然存在 ♪
我的生活发生了很多变化
A lot has changed about my life.
但是无论我去哪儿  人们总是问我同一个问题
But everywhere I go, people ask me the same thing.
♪ And they've turned around   他们已经转身离去 ♪
你可以和我的狗合个影吗
Can you take a picture with my dog?
♪ Who'd have thought they'd lead ya   谁能想到他们会指引你 ♪
"斯科特  你现在有什么打算"
"Scott, what about now?
♪ Back here where we need ya   回到我们需要你的地方 ♪
"你下一步计划做什么"
"What's next?
"你人生的路去往何方"
"Where does the ride take you?"
如果我都知道了  那人生还有什么乐趣呢
If I knew that, it wouldn't be a ride.
♪ Yeah we tease him a lot   我们经常戏谑他 ♪
这谁家小孩
All right.
♪ Cause we got him on the spot   因为我们让他无处可逃 ♪
-对所有人来说  这几年超级疯狂   -嘿  嗨  你好吗
-It's been a crazy few years. For everyone.   -Hey, hi. How are you?
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
都给你准备好了
Everything is ready for you.
你们太贴心了
You're too much.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
我们这不收你钱
Your money's no good here.
-咋还来这一套   -必须的啊
-Are we still talking about that?   -Yes, of course.
♪ We always could spot a friend   我们总能找到朋友 ♪
鲁宾  你最棒了
Rubin, you are the best.
谢谢你  蜘蛛侠
Thank you, Spider-Man.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
♪ And I smile when I think how you must have been   当我想起你过去的模样  我微微一笑 ♪
所以咱们应该把时间花在真正重要的事情上
So, let's make time for the stuff that really matters.
比如朋友
Like friends.
♪ And I know what a scene you were learning in   我知道你见多识广 ♪
那些你还没结识的新朋友
Friends you didn't even know you had.
♪ Was there something that made you come back again  是不是有什么原因让你再次回来 ♪
本世纪最佳员工
斯科特·朗  "蚁人"
记住把你带到这里来的人
Remember the people who got you here.
本世纪最佳员工
斯科特·朗  "蚁人"
美国31冰淇淋
没有他们就没有现在的你
You couldn't have done it without them.
♪ And what could ever lead ya   究竟是什么指引着你 ♪
嘿  要知道我还是个被美国31冰淇淋炒了鱿鱼的人
Hey, I'm just a guy who got fired from Baskin-Robbins.
♪ Back here where we need ya   回到我们需要你的地方 ♪
有时候你就是会走运
Sometimes you just get lucky.
我很幸运遇到了霍普·凡·戴恩
I'm lucky I met Hope Van Dyne.
♪ Yeah we tease him a lot   我们经常戏谑他 ♪
我想你们知道她是谁
I think you know who she is.
♪ Cause we got him on the spot   因为我们让他无处可逃 ♪
皮姆·凡·戴恩
基金会
她已经接手了她父亲的公司
She's taken back her dad's company.
皮姆·凡·戴恩
基金会
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
现在她致力于使用皮姆粒子造福全球
Now she's using the Pym Particle for global change.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
很多人都说他们想拯救世界...
A lot of people say they want to save the world...
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
国际人道主义服务奖
但是霍普  她每天都在把一切付诸实践
but Hope, she saves it every day.
国际人道主义服务奖
♪ Yeah we tease him a lot   我们经常戏谑他 ♪
谢谢大家
Thank you.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
非常感谢大家
Thank you so much.
♪ Cause we got him on the spot   因为我们让他无处可逃 ♪
植树造林  平价住宅  粮食生产
Reforestation. Affordable housing. Food production.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
♪ Yeah we tease him a lot   我们经常戏谑他 ♪
她不浪费一分一秒
She's not wasting a second.
♪ Cause we got him on the spot   因为我们让他无处可逃 ♪
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
我到现在还不敢相信
I still can't believe it.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
这一切本不该发生
None of this should have happened.
但就是发生了
But it did.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
这是一个美好的世界
It's a pretty good world.
我很高兴我们拯救了它
I'm glad we saved it.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
"我会怀念以前的作战吗"
"Do I miss the action?
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
城
市
之
光
书
店
不可忽视的小人物
斯科特·朗
"有时候会"
"Sometimes.
斯科特·朗
不可忽视的小人物
"当复仇者联盟需要我的时候我会到场吗"
"Will I be there when the Avengers need me?
斯科特·朗
"绝对地"
"Absolutely.
"我永远都不会背弃他们"
"I'd never turn my back on them.
"但是现在  我唯一的工作就是当一个好父亲"
"But right now, the only job I want is being a dad.
"我爱你  凯茜"
"I love you, Cassie.
谢谢你成为我的英雄"
"Thanks for being my hero.
"我很抱歉错过你好些年的生日"
"And I'm sorry I missed some birthdays.
"对于你们其他的孩子来说"
"And for the rest of you kids out there...
"出于本人的忠告"
"word of advice.
"不要忽视小人物"
"Look out for the little guy.
"敢于犯错"
"Make mistakes.
"抓住机会"
"Take chances.
"因为如果说生活教会了我一件事"
"Because if there's one thing life's taught me...
"那就是我们总有成长的空间"
"there's always room to grow."
抱歉  是我的电话
Sorry, that's me.
旧金山监狱
为什么是监狱打给我的
Why is jail calling?
朗
Lang!
-朗   -我在这儿
-Lang!   -I'm here.
好吧  来吧  我们走
All right, come on. Let's go.
快点
Come on.
嘿  她还好吗  你知道咋回事吗
Hey. Is she okay? Have you heard anything?
还没有
Not yet. No.
嗨  霍普  嘿  老爸
Hi, Hope. Hey, Dad.
凯茜  发生什么事了
Cassie. What happened?
在这签字
Sign here.
你懂的  只是日常蹲牢
You know, just jail stuff.
给我交回来
Give it back.
我知道是你干的
I know it was you.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我意思是  你向公园里的和平抗议者们扔了好些催泪瓦斯
I mean, it was kind of hard to see through all that tear gas you fired...
那么大的烟你怎么能看清楚...
into the park full of peaceful protestors.
它在哪儿
Where is it?
不好意思  这对你来说肯定很尴尬
I'm sorry. This must be really embarrassing for you.
不过我当时捡到它了
I did find this though.
你缩小了一辆警车  你脑袋里在想什么
You shrank a cop car? What were you thinking?
那我应该做什么  袖手旁观吗
What was I supposed to do? Look the other way?
他们在半夜里清理一个流浪汉营地
They were clearing out a homeless camp in the middle of the night.
-不  我不是这个意思...   -那他们还能去哪
-No, I'm not saying that...   -And where do they expect them to go?
在烁灭期间失去自己的家又不是他们的错
It's not their fault that they lost their homes in the Blip.
那些我知道
I know that.
除了那些家里有矿的富二代  现在甚至没人能付得起房租
No one can even afford rent right now, unless you're some trust-fund asshole.
我并不是在教你做事
I'm not telling you what to do.
-我只是想说...   -教她做事
-I'm just saying...   -Telling her what to do.
-就是想教我做事   -不  你可以做你想做的
-Telling me exactly what to do.   -No, you do what you want.
我只是建议你可以用别的方式去做
I'm suggesting another way to do it.
好的
Okay.
你明白的  我答应你妈妈...
You know, I promised your mom...
我俩至少有一个在你旁边的时候才能用这些玩意
that you would only use this stuff when one of us was around.
这是很危险的技术
It's really dangerous tech.
我知道它很危险
I know it's dangerous.
如果那些警察没收了呢  如果你把它们弄丢了呢
What if the cops took it from you? What if you lost it?
我可没弄丢战衣
I didn't lose the suit.
你有战衣
You have a suit?
等等  你还有战衣
Wait, you have a suit?
我能照顾好自己  好吗
I know how to take care of myself, okay?
相信我  我现在可擅长了
Trust me. I'm pretty good at it by now.
扎心了
Ouch.
-我不是那个意思  抱歉   -我知道
-I didn't mean it like that. I'm sorry.   -I know.
没关系  没关系
That's okay. It's all right.
我明白
I get it.
我只是觉得你应该拥有一个正常的人生
I just think you should get to have a normal life.
老爸  我六岁的时候  一个穿得像蜜蜂的人
Dad, a guy dressed like a bee...
想在我的房间里杀了我
tried to kill me in my room when I was six.
我的人生注定不普通
I've never had a normal life.
来点音乐不
How about some music?
"在那个时候  我脑子里只有一个念头"
"And in that moment, all I could think was...
"浩克是怎么把我变成一个婴儿的"
"'How did the Hulk turn me into a baby?
"我会永远是一个婴儿吗"
"'Will I be a baby forever?
"我会算是浩克的孩子吗"
"'Am I the Hulk's baby?'"
老爹  你不会在听你自己的书吧
Dad, are you listening to your own book?
-"但是我做好了一切准备"   -嗯  不  那是...
-"But I was ready for anything.   -Hmm? No, that's...
-只是广播罢了   -"史蒂夫和我关系越来越好"
-It's just the radio.   -"Steve and I grew close over that."
-爸爸  把它关了   -太奇怪了
-Dad, turn it off.   -It's so weird.
这个开关出了点问题  它关不掉
Something's wrong with this switch. It won't turn off.
别闹了快把它关了
I said turn it off.
什么  把它调高  好吧
What's that? Turn it up? All right.
"不一会儿  一只太空浣熊出现在我面前"
"A little after that, a raccoon from space showed up.
"我觉得他不认识我"
"I don't think he knew my name.
"我只是很高兴能遇见一只会说话的浣熊"
"I was just happy to meet a raccoon who could talk."
让一让
Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
来吧
All right.
你的诺贝尔奖已经在路上了
Your Nobel Prize is in the mail.
最好是这样  我可给家里省下八块钱呢
It better be. I just saved eight bucks.
天哪  我太崇拜你了
God, I admire you.
多谢
Thank you.
我太想念这一切了
I missed this.
在量子领域没有披萨吗
No pizza in the Quantum Realm?
不  那什么都没有
No. No anything.
你知道吗  妈妈  你可以和我们说说这些
You know, Mom, you can talk about it.
如果你愿意的话
If you want.
宝贝  我在那度过了30年
Sweetheart, I spent 30 years down there.
我只想好好享受当下
I wanna live right now.
那么  凯茜  这一次你进局子有交什么新朋友吗
So, Cassie, did you make any new friends in the slammer this time?
外公
Grandpa.
什么叫"这一次"
"This time"?
难道还有上一次吗
Was there a last time?
我意思是  上一次基本不算数
I mean, last time barely counts.
我毫不知情
I didn't know that.
你为什么不联系我
Why didn't you call me?
因为我就知道你会这样
'Cause I knew you'd be like this.
其实我可以派蚂蚁去救你出狱
I would've just broken you out with ants.
好吧  你们知道吗  家庭会议
All right, you know what? Family meeting.
我们可以开家庭会议吗
Can we have a family meeting?
这不就是我们现在在做的吗
Isn't that what we're doing?
对  我说的是凯茜的事
Yeah, I mean about this.
并且所有人都在纵容她
About everybody being so fine with this.
听着  你想帮忙  我理解
Look, you wanna help. I get it.
我明白  凯茜  我真的明白
I do, Cassie. I really do.
但是我不想你浪费你的人生
But I don't want you wasting your life.
至少我还在试着努力做点什么
At least I'm still trying to do something with mine.
我可是货真价实地拯救了世界
I literally saved the world.
哦  是吗
Oh, did you?
好啊  你之前可从来没提过
Well, yeah, you never mentioned that before.
嘿  大家听着  斯科特拯救世界了
Hey, everybody, Scott saved the world.
那是什么感觉  斯科特
How was that for you, Scott?
你应该为此写本书
You should write a book about it.
哈  哈  真幽默
Ha ha. Hilarious.
多亏了我你们才全都没有化灰  不用谢
Yeah, you're welcome for all not being dust.
那你现在在忙什么
And what do you do now?
给书签名
Sign books?
你不是那个闯入维斯塔公司的人吗
Aren't you the guy who broke into VistaCorp?
你不是那个大老远飞去德国
Aren't you the guy who flew all the way to Germany...
只是为了在机场和美国队长干架的人吗
just to fight Captain America at the airport?
在机场是帮美国队长干架
Fight with Captain America at the airport.
我怎么可能跟美国队长打
Wouldn't fight Captain America.
我发疯了吗
Not insane.
人们仍然需要帮助  爸爸
People still need help, Dad.
至少我们在试着去做有用的事
At least we're trying to do something that matters.
哪来的"我们"
Who's "we"?
你们三个又在做什么
What are you three up to?
科学
Science.
关于蚂蚁的
With ants.
蚂蚁科学
Ant science.
我才不信你
I don't believe you.
让我们给他看看
Let's just show him.
他们在造什么
What are they building?
是你操纵它们的吗
Are you doing this?
实际上不是  它们在建立自己的科技
Actually, no, they built their own tech.
非常聪明的蚂蚁们
Pretty smart ants.
所以当你们大家都...
Okay, so when you were all...
消失的这五年  我空出来许多时间
like, gone those five years, I had a lot of time.
于是我开始阅读汉克外公的那些旧日志...
And I started reading Grandpa Hank's old journals...
并且逐渐被量子领域所吸引
and I got really into the Quantum Realm and...
你说的是那个量子领域嘛
The Quantum Realm?
我知道在座各位都不是很想提它  而且我也不想吓到任何一个人
I know we all have a history there, and I didn't want to freak anyone out...
但是我们一直在讨论它
but we've been talking about it.
她就是有些疑问  好吗
She had some questions, okay?
如果人们受到我的启发  我可拦不住啊
I can't help if people are inspired by me.
所以  你一直在研究量子领域吗
So, you've been studying the Quantum Realm?
你之前怎么不找我问问
Why didn't you ask me about it?
我问过  妈妈
I tried, Mom.
很多次
A lot.
你从来都不愿意和我说
You never wanted to talk about it.
凯茜只是出于好奇...  于是我们就提供一些指导
Cassie's just been curious... and we gave her some pointers.
这并不是蚂蚁科学  对吧  亨利
This isn't exactly ant science, is it, Henry?
你很清楚量子领域有多危险
You know how dangerous the Quantum Realm is.
是的  我们都知道  妈妈  没有人要去量子领域
Yeah, we all do, Mom. Nobody's going to the Quantum Realm.
这就为什么我们造了这个
That's why we made this.
它就好像探测深空或者深海的卫星
It's like a satellite for deep space or the ocean.
但是探测的...
But...
是量子领域
Quantum.
我们只需要一张地图
We just need a map.
就可以研究和探索整个量子领域
And then we can study and explore the entire Quantum Realm.
甚至都不需要亲自去
Never even have to go.
你的女儿在地下室造出了一台亚原子级的哈勃望远镜
Your daughter built a subatomic Hubble Telescope in a basement.
你懂的  如果在你消失的那段时间我有这个的话...
You know, if I had something like this when you were gone...
那我就可以找到你
then I could have found you.
这很了不起
It's amazing.
我都被你震撼了
I'm blown away.
这个是怎么运作的
How does it work?
它有点像我们以前那台双向无线电
It's kinda like that two-way radio we used to have.
你从这儿发送一个信号...
You send a signal down from here...
然后它收集完数据发送回来
and then it collects the data, and it sends it back.
等下  稍等一会
Wait. Wait a minute.
你正在向量子领域发送信号
You're sending a signal down to the Quantum Realm?
是的
Yeah.
赶紧把它关了
Shut it down now.
-珍妮特...   -为什么我们要关了...
-Janet...   -Why would we shut it...
-有什么问题吗   -你必须把它关了
-What's wrong?   -You have to turn it off!
别这样  告诉我们哪出错了
Stop and tell us what's wrong!
珍妮特
Janet?
有一些事情我应该早点告诉...
There's something I should have told...
爸爸
Dad?
不
No!
-不   -妈妈
-No!   -Mom!
不
No!
该死
Damn it!
爸爸
Dad?
Dad!
爸爸
凯茜
Cassie.
爸爸
Dad!
哦  爸爸  快起来
Oh, Dad. Come on.
好
Okay.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
嗯  我没事
Yeah. I'm okay.
我们在哪
Where are we?
妈妈
Mom!
爸爸
Dad!
霍普  我在这儿
Hope. Over here.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我们应该死了才对
We should be dead.
那我们怎么没死
Why aren't we?
我不知道
I don't know.
这是我想的那个地方吗
Are we where I think we are?
我觉得应该是...
I would say yes...
但是它之前不是这样的  珍妮特
but it wasn't like this. Janet!
妈妈
Mom!
珍妮特
Janet!
妈妈
Mom!
待在这不要动
Do not move.
我们需要找到斯科特和凯茜
We need to find Scott and Cassie.
立刻马上
Right now.
霍普  霍普
Hope? Hope?
汉克  你们能听见吗
Hank? Can you hear me?
-有人能听见我吗   -我的老天
-Can anyone hear me?   -Oh, my God.
-没事的   -接下来我们该怎么做
-It's okay.   -What are we gonna do?
没事  没事  我们会没事的
It's okay. It's okay. We're okay.
-没事  都会没事的   -别再一个劲地说"没事"了
-We're okay. It's gonna be okay.   -You're saying "okay" too much.
好的  没问题  好的  因为事实就是我们没事
Okay. All right. Okay. Well, it's 'cause we are.
我们会没事的
We're okay.
不会有事的
We are fine.
嘿  我们会找到他们  然后我们就会回家
Hey, we're gonna find them, and we're gonna go home.
趁现在 看看周围的风景  多么绚丽多彩
In the meantime, look around. It's beautiful.
好吗  我们只是到户外
All right? We're outside.
就好像在露营  我们喜欢露营
It's like we're camping. We love camping.
我们从来都没露营过
We've never been camping.
但是我们经常说要去
But we've always talked about it.
那个太阳在动吗
Is that sun moving?
退后
Get back!
哦  我的天哪
Oh, my God.
我觉得这不是什么太阳
I don't think this is a sun!
没事
It's fine.
-爸爸   -宝贝  我没事
-Dad!   -Honey, it's okay.
还能应付
Still okay.
爸爸  哦  我的天呐
Dad. Oh, my God.
那太诡异了
That was weird.
跑
Run.
那是量子领域里的量子人吗
There's Quantum people in the Quantum Realm?
是吧
Yeah.
我也不知道那是什么
I didn't know that either.
刚刚那个是什么  妈妈
What was that back there, Mom?
那个飞船在找什么
What was that ship looking for?
都小点儿声
Keep your voice down.
你说过这下面什么东西都没有
You said there was nothing down here.
-你为什么闭口不谈   -霍普  我会向你们解释一切的
-Why didn't you tell us about all of this?   -Hope, I will explain everything,
-但是现在我只需要你相信我   -那你拿出让我相信你的证据
-but right now... I just need you to trust me.   -Then make me trust you!
都冷静一会  好吗  我们可以好好谈谈....
Let's just calm down, all right? We can talk about this...
我们没时间谈  亨利
We don't have time to talk, Henry.
-不  你必须告诉我们什么是...   -那你为什么不听我说的话
-No, you need to tell us what's...   -Why didn't you listen?
我告诉过你们不要碰量子领域
I told you to stay away from here.
珍妮特  对不起
Janet, I'm so sorry.
我应该告诉你我们在做什么  我不知道...
I should have told you what we were doing. I had no idea...
我知道  这...
I know. It's...
我们待会儿再说这个
We'll talk later.
现在开始  我们一定要待在一起...
Right now, we stick together...
去找到斯科特和凯茜
we find Scott and Cassie...
然后我们就回家  好吗
and we go home. Okay?
-行吗   -好
-Okay?   -Okay?
-好   -好的
-Okay.   -Okay.
跟紧点
Stay close.
这真是难以置信
This is incredible.
我研究量子领域这么多年了
I've studied the Quantum Realm for years.
为什么没有发现这些
Why didn't I see any of this?
你只看到了表象
You weren't able to look deep enough.
没有通过虚空和亚原子态进行观察
Not through the Void and Subatomica.
这里有许许多多的世界...
There are worlds here...
世界之中又包含其他世界
worlds within worlds.
量子领域是时间和空间之外的领域
It's a place outside time and space.
是一个存在于我们宇宙之下...
It's a secret universe...
另一个隐秘的宇宙
beneath ours.
喂  把手拿开
Hey, get your hands off me!
凯茜
Cassie?
我女儿在哪儿
Where's my daughter?
她在哪儿
Where is she?
凯茜
Cassie?
我女儿在哪
Where's my daughter?
凯茜
Cassie!
爸爸
Dad!
凯茜
Cassie!
把那个悟汁喝了
Drink the ooze.
啥玩意儿
What?
我来处理这个
I'll handle this.
妈
Mom.
刚刚那是友好地捅一下吗
Was that a good stab?
我找了个便车
I got us a ride.
他很亲人
He's friendly.
真奇葩的便车
Quite a ride.
你骑着蚂蚁飞也不好到哪儿去
Says the man who invented flying on the back of an ant.
我爱蚂蚁
I like ants.
那我真的太欣慰了  来吧
And I love that you love them. Here.
这些衣服能帮我们混进去
These will help us blend in.
我们到底要去哪儿啊
Where exactly are we going on this?
我有一个老朋友就在这附近
We're not too far from an old friend of mine.
如果说有谁知道斯科特和凯茜的下落的话...
If anyone's heard where Scott and Cassie are...
那个人肯定是他
it'll be him.
请吧
After you.
上车吧  蚁人
Saddle up, Ant-Man.
放开我  放开我
Let me go! Let me go!
我听不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you're saying!
我听不懂你...
I don't know what you...
别  别
No! No!
喝悟汁
Drink the ooze!
你好啊
Hello.
你好  你好
Hi. Hi.
你把悟汁喝了吗
Did you drink the ooze?
我现在为什么能听懂你说话了
Why can I understand you?
太棒了  就是因为你喝了悟汁
Great. That's the ooze.
嘿  大家伙  悟汁起作用啦
Hey, everybody, it worked! Ooze worked!
我们终于能当朋友了
We can finally be friends.
你好啊  我叫维布
Hi. I am Veb.
你刚刚喝了我的一部分
You just drank me.
啥...我喝了什么
I did... What?
你还要再来点悟汁吗  给你
Do you need some more ooze? Here.
-我可以直接喂进你的洞洞里哦...   -别了别了  我喝够了
-I can pour some ooze into your hole...   -No, I'm okay.
-我喝好了  喝好了   -好吧  哇哦
-I'm okay. I'm okay.   -Oh, wow!
好大一个洞
A big hole.
你身上有几个洞啊
How many holes do you have?
抱歉  这应该算是个私人问题吧
I'm sorry. Is that a personal question?
我身上一个洞都没有
I don't have any holes.
他叫斯科特·朗
His name is Scott Lang.
他身上有七个洞
He has seven holes.
太对了
Yeah, that's right.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
他叫夸兹  他会心灵感应
He's Quaz. He's a telepath.
你会读心术吗
You can read minds?
对  我倒是希望我不会
Yeah, and I really wish I couldn't.
这儿的每个人都好恶心
Everyone is disgusting.
-你能别那么想了吗   -抱歉
-Could you please stop thinking that?   -Sorry.
-求你了  别这样了   -别想了吗
-Please, stop.   -Thinking?
-别想那事儿了   -我尽量
-Thinking that.   -I'm trying.
这不是很难吧  我觉得你也怪怪的
Well, not very hard. And I think you look weird too.
我不觉得你奇怪啊  我觉得你太酷了
I don't think you look weird. I think you look really cool.
我也希望我脑袋闪闪发光
I wish my head glowed.
不不不  你没说实话
No, no, you don't.
我确实不想脑袋发光  只是有点紧张  所以这想法就冒了出来
I know I don't. I'm nervous, okay? And it just came out.
你来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
-你是间谍吗   -什么玩意儿  不不不
-Are you a spy?   -What? No. No, no.
-我们应该给他上上酷刑   -大家别激动  没事的
-We should torture him.   -Guys. No, it's okay.
我们不是间谍  他是我爸爸
We're not spies. He's my dad.
-谢谢你   -不客气
-Thank you.   -Welcome.
那旧金山又是谁
Then who is San Francisco?
-我们是打那儿来的   -那是一个地方
-It's where we're from.   -It's a place.
那地球又是什么东西
Then what's Earth?
那也是我们来的地方
It's also where we're from.
我们应该给他上酷刑拷问了
We should torture them.
你为啥老是想着折磨别人  明明还有其他办法的
Why are you always trying to torture people? We have other options.
你的洞洞里会流东西出来吗  比如牛奶  果汁啥的...
Do things come out of your holes, like milk, juice...
维布  别逮着他的洞问个不停了
Veb, stop asking about his holes.
我们也不是都没有洞
Some of us have holes.
你来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
你从哪儿来的
Where are you from?
-好吧   -我从上面来的
-Okay.   -Up there. Up there.
-就从你们的头顶上来的  一个不同的宇宙   -我们来自地球  大地球
-See, above this, it's a different universe.   -The Earth. Big Earth.
-跟你们处在同一个宇宙  但是更大一些   -你们这里是缩小版的地球
-It's the same universe, but it's bigger.   -This is Earth, but it's a very small Earth.
-应该是这样的   -我能变大  还能缩小
-Sometimes, I guess.   -I get big. I shrink.
-这就像是...   -我还写了本书呢
-And it's like...   -But I wrote a book about it, actually.
-我也不好说   -这里是量子领域
-I don't know.   -This is the Quantum Realm.
必须缩小才能进入量子领域
You have to shrink to get in the Quantum Realm.
-我们现在非常非常小   -在地球我们的体型会更大一点
-We shrunk. Right now, we're really small.   -It's bigger where we're from.
-所以  我们现在就是小小的   -在地球就会更大
-So, we're small right now.   -It's bigger.
好  他们没有说谎
Okay, they're telling the truth.
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
你们是从上面来的
You come from above.
就像他一样
Like him.
所以  他也会追捕你们
So, he is hunting you.
他会不惜一切代价找到你们
He will burn the world to find you.
谁
Who?
征服者
The Conqueror.
量子领域下居然真有生物  还是智慧生物
There are beings down here. Intelligent beings.
我一直以为这些只是理论  直到现在亲自到访...
I always theorized it was possible, but to be here...
一个亚原子宇宙
a subatomic universe.
这将会颠覆我们对生命所熟知的一切...
This changes everything we know about life...
以及我们对进化的观点  还有我们在银河系中的位置...
evolution, our place in the galaxy...
我去
Holy shit!
这玩意儿怎么看起来像颗西兰花
That guy looks like broccoli.
低调点小心走
Keep your head down.
跟我来
Follow me.
喝这个
Drink those.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
我来找克里拉
I'm here for Krylar.
是你
It's you.
悄悄的  我们俩心里明白就行
Let's keep that between us.
还有记得帮我找克里拉
And Krylar.
你好
Hello.
虽然我不太懂你们的习俗...
I don't know your ways or customs...
但我猜你们一定有像酒的饮料对吧
but I assume that you have a beverage that can get me drunk?
必须有
Absolutely, sir.
美女一定是个有故事的人吧
So, what's your story then?
我的天
God.
滚
Move.
该走了
It's time.
跟我来
Follow me.
这边请
Right this way.
你怎么认识这个人的
How exactly do you know this guy?
是我的老朋友了  自由斗士
Old freedom fighter friend of mine.
等等  你之前是自由斗士吗
Sorry, you were a freedom fighter?
或者说恐怖分子
Or terrorist.
要看你问谁了
Depends on who you ask.
但相信我  他能帮上忙
But, trust me, he can help.
珍妮特·凡·戴恩
Janet Van Dyne?
我以为你已经与世长辞了
I thought you were dead.
好久不见了  克里拉
Been a long time, Krylar.
我现在可是克里拉勋爵了
Officially, Lord Krylar now.
虽然我不太喜欢这个称号
I fought like hell against that.
太精英主义了
It sounds so elitist.
您一定是汉克对吧
You have got to be Hank.
久仰您和您蚂蚁的大名
I've heard so much about you and your ants.
话说蚂蚁是啥玩意
What are ants anyway?
我们这儿有蚂蚁吗
Do we have 'em down here?
应该是没有
I don't think so. No.
遗憾
That's too bad.
霍普
Hope.
你一定就是霍普了
You have to be Hope.
你妈妈每天都在念叨着你
She talked about you every day.
好怪哦...她从来没有提到过你
That's strange... she never said anything about you.
换我我也不会告诉我的孩子
I don't think I would have told my kid either.
-我那些狂野的过往   -有趣
-Wild stuff.   -Funny.
有多狂野
How wild?
相当狂野  亨利  太狂野了
Very wild, Henry. Yeah.
克里拉  我们需要你帮忙
Krylar, we need your help.
珍妮特  我们一起走过这么多风风雨雨...
Janet, after all we've been through, together...
你直说就行了
just ask me.
告诉我  我能帮上什么
Tell me, how can I help?
但是...
But...
有人饿了吗  我快饿死了
is anyone starving? I'm starving.
小伙子们...
Boys...
现在就端上来吧
Now.
他们啥也不知道
They don't know anything.
完全一无所知
About... anything.
那就把他们送走吧
Then get them out of here.
借过一下
Excuse me.
他说得对  我们真的啥都不知道
Look, he's right. I don't know what's going on.
我们只想找到我们的家人
We're just trying to find our family.
你有地图吗
Do you have a map?
我们只是想回...
All we wanna do is go...
别别别  别开枪
Wait, wait. Don't shoot.
他们是我们的人
They're with us.
这栋楼是活的吗
Is that building alive?
你们世界的楼是死的吗
Yours are dead?
嘿  再打扰一下
Look. Excuse me.
我们只想回家
We just wanna go home.
你好歹还有个家回
At least you still have a home.
你们的世界遭遇了什么
What happened here?
征服者毁灭了我们的家
The Conqueror burned our homes.
毁灭了我们的文明
Our stories.
他用我们人民的尸骨构筑了他的城堡
He built his citadel on the bones of our people.
我们其中一些人逃了出来...
Some of us escaped...
找到了其他逃亡的人
found others on the run.
我们尽可能地聚集了有战斗能力的人
We gathered who we could to fight.
但这远远不够
It was never enough.
对你们的遭遇我深感抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们能帮忙
We can help.
-凯茜...   -爸  你可是复仇者
-Cassie...   -Dad, you're an Avenger.
-他们需要帮助   -不
-They need help.   -No.
现在我要做的事情就是把你送回家
What I need to do is get you home.
你为什么不想帮助他们
Why don't you wanna help?
我们对这个宇宙一无所知
We don't know anything about this place.
甚至都不知道这里时间运行的机制
I mean, I don't even know how time works down here.
我们在这里被困了十秒钟  还是十年都不清楚
Have we been gone for 10 seconds? Or have we been gone for 10 years?
想想你妈妈现在是什么样的心情
Think about your mom right now.
-你想想  她现在一定...   -别拿妈妈当借口
-Can you imagine what she must be...   -Don't use Mom as an excuse.
-你根本就不在乎   -不  我在乎
-You just don't care.   -No, I do care.
我懂你想帮忙  我真的懂
I know you wanna help. I do.
但这不是我们要打的仗
But this is not our fight.
我们没有遭遇这样的不幸
Just 'cause it's not happening to you
并不代表天下太平
doesn't mean it's not happening.
嘿
Hey.
看看我好吗
Would you look at me?
她对你很失望
She's disappointed in you.
我知道  谢谢你
I got that. Yeah. Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我们待会儿再讨论这个问题
We'll talk about it later.
现在  我们必须找到其他人
Right now, let's just find the others.
珍妮特最懂这个地方
No one knows this place better than Janet.
你说什么
What did you say?
我说啥了
What?
那个名字
That name.
珍妮特·凡·戴恩
Janet Van Dyne.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
我们一直在找她  你认识她吗
That's what we're trying to find out. You know her?
我认识她
I know her.
她不应该来这儿
She shouldn't be here.
嘿  把那些醒酒汤拿过来
Hey, bring a round of the chasers, please.
谢谢你
Yes, thank you.
如果你没喝过这个的话  千万别尝...
If you haven't had this, don't try it...
除非你想彻底颠覆你的人生
unless you want to change your life.
克里拉  我们在找朋友
Krylar, we're looking for friends of ours.
两个人
Two of them.
人类  就像我们一样
Human, like us.
人类  对  就是这个词
Human, that's the word.
我都忘了在地球你们管自己叫人类
Totally forgot what you call yourselves up there.
人类
Human.
你不是人类吗
Are you not human?
不是严格意义上的人类  但我算是吧
Not technically, but yes.
至少有用的那些构造跟人一样
In the ways that matter.
别
No!
让我们谈谈
Let us talk.
所以  什么风把你吹来了  珍妮特
So, what is it that brings you to us, Janet?
如果我没记错的话  你走了
If I remember correctly, you left.
你抛下了我们所有人
You left all of us.
让我们独自面对他
With him.
珍妮特  他在说什么
Janet, what is he talking about?
你没告诉他你在这儿的经历吧
You didn't tell them about him.
你有没有提到过...
Did you say anything...
你在这里做的事情
about what you did here?
多少人因你丧命
How many people died because of you?
你的家人知道你的真实身份吗
Does your family even know who you are?
你的老妈...
Your mommy...
可是有很多秘密的
is full of secrets.
你在说谎
You're lying.
确实
I lie.
我说过很多谎
A lot.
但这件事我没说谎
Not about this.
放他们走
Let them go.
他想要的是我
He just wants me.
但你想要他们啊  所以他们也要一起来
But you want them. So they're coming too.
还有你的其他朋友
Along with those other friends of yours.
我听说了
I heard about them.
他同样也知道
But he did too.
他还派出了猎人
And he sent the Hunter.
什么猎人
What kind of hunter?
不是人  不是机器
Not a man. Not a machine.
而是一个只为杀戮设计的机械有机复合体
A mechanized organism designed only for killing.
他们在哪儿
Where are they?
不知道
No clue.
死
Dead.
也有可能没死
Probably dead.
这真让人伤心啊...
This is so sad when all of this...
这一切本都可以避免  珍妮特
could have been avoided, Janet.
把他想要的东西给他就行了
Just give him what he wants.
你怎么变成这样了
What happened to you?
我们曾一起并肩作战抵抗他
We fought against him.
他给了我一个无法拒绝的条件
He can be very persuasive.
我们去拜访一下他吧
Let's pay him a visit.
我们谈好了
I think we're done here.
这艘船能带我们离开这儿吗
Can that ship get us out of here?
来点掩护
Cover me?
一如既往
Always.
亨利  掌舵
Henry, take the helm.
我来短接发动飞艇
I'm gonna hot-wire this thing.
控制台在哪儿
Where are the controls?
那些就是控制器
Those are the controls.
什么玩意儿
What the hell?
你没问题的  就像骑着单车飞一样
You'll be great. It's like flying a bike.
这单车怎么是活的
Is the bike alive?
手伸到底  全速推进
Hands, all the way in!
就像给火鸡填料那样
Like stuffing a turkey.
-真的吗  你跟他   -他以前还算魅力四射
-Really, him?  -He used to be charming.
那家伙吗
That guy?
亨利  我一个人在这儿待了30年
I was down here for 30 years, Henry.
-我也有需求啊   -天啊
-I had needs.   -Oh, my God.
我理解  我也有需求
Look, I get it. I've got needs too.
快别说了
Oh, my God!
我也和别人约过几次饭
I had dinner with someone a few times.
她叫琳达
Her name was Linda.
但最后没成
It didn't work out.
为什么没成
What went wrong?
因为她到底不是你  宝贝
She wasn't you, baby.
-叫所有人都上船  我们得走了   -好
-Get everyone in the ships. We're leaving.   -All right.
-左伦   -在
-And, Xolum.   -Right here.
叫他们有多远滚多远
Take them as far away from here as you can.
-为什么   -什么
-Why?   -What?
如果你们在找珍妮特  那他一定也在找你们
If you're looking for Janet, he's looking for you.
你把他们引到这儿来了
You led them straight to us.
快跑
Come on, come on.
尽量多带些人走
Take as many as you can.
我们拖住敌人
We'll hold them off.
快跑
Go!
快点  快跑
Come on! Hurry, hurry!
我们得赶紧走了
We gotta go! We gotta go!
快上船  快点
Get on. Get on now!
得赶紧离开
We have to go now. Now!
天啊
Oh, my God!
凯茜  快走了
Cassie, let's go!
去避难所
Get to the sanctuary.
等我消息
Wait for my message.
-维布  得走了   -不  等等
-Veb, we're leaving.   -No. No, wait!
-快上船   -我的朋友们
-Move! Move!   -All my friends.
交出旅行者
Give up the travelers.
征服者会宽恕你们的
The Conqueror will show you mercy.
我见识过他的宽恕了
I know his mercy.
待在这里  我...
Stay here. I'm...
凯茜
Cassie?
坏了
Oh, no.
我说实话  我确实有战衣
Okay. I have a suit.
是啊  我发现了
Yeah, I noticed.
-你还好吗   -我没事
-You okay?   -Yes.
听好了  借势发力
Look, momentum, right?
起跳  肘击  懂了吗  一气呵成  飞身一击
Jump, tap, right? One move. Jump, tap.
我知道怎么做  老爸
I know how to do it, Dad.
-你知道  真的吗   -真的
-Do you? Really?   -Yes.
-我看着可不像   -我没算准时间
-'Cause it didn't look like it from my end.   -I messed up on the timing.
起跳...
Jump...
就像这样
Like that.
看见我刚才的示范了吗  看清了吗
You see what I did? You see what I did?
并没有  你刚刚就那么大点
No. You're like this small.
我飞身一击了
I jumped and tapped.
詹托拉  得走了
Jentorra, we have to go.
上飞船
Get to the ship!
欢迎回到量子领域  斯科特
Welcome back to the Quantum Realm, Scott.
我等这一刻很久了
I've been waiting a long time for this.
啥
What?
有人在里面吗
Is someone in there?
当然了
Oh, yes.
我是你无法逃离的宿命...
The destiny you cannot escape.
我们的命运早就被绑在一起
Our fates have always been forged together...
自从我们相遇那天起
ever since that day we met.
斯科特·朗
Scott Lang.
-离我们远点   -也就是你打败我的那一天
-Get away from us!   -The day you broke me.
-是你害我流落至此   -等等
-Banished me down here.   -Wait.
你是达伦
Darren?
见到我惊不惊喜
Surprised to see me?
是啊
Yeah.
他是那个蜜蜂男吗
It's the bee guy?
-他是蜜蜂男吧   -凯茜
-It's the bee guy?   -Cassie?
我差点没认出你来
I almost didn't recognize you.
你怎么活下来的
How are you not dead?
我现在是终极武器了
I became the ultimate weapon.
这玩意是终极武器吗
That's what this is?
听着  达伦
Look, Darren.
达伦已经死了
Darren is dead!
这里只有魔多客
There is only M.O.D.O.K.!
你已经无路可逃了  斯科特
And there's no place you can run, Scott.
逃不过我
Not from me.
更逃不出他的掌心
And not from him.
他是未来
He's the future.
也是过去
He's the past.
现在他需要的就是你
And now all he needs is you.
妈妈
Mom?
谁要抓斯科特和凯茜
What's after Scott and Cassie?
我们得去找他们
We have to find them.
我得先办一些别的事
There's something I have to do first.
他们可能会被杀的
They could be dead!
霍普  冷静点
Hope, please.
-你到现在了还有事瞒着我们   -我是为了
-And you're still hiding things from us.   -I am trying
保护你们不受伤害
to protect you.
受什么伤害
From what?
是谁让你这么害怕
Who are you so afraid of?
这是你第三次蹲监狱吧
Third time in jail?
我第四次
Four.
此情此景  我们两个人
And here we are again.
面对面
Face to face.
你这个面  真的是...
That's a face. It's a...
好大一面
big face.
你为什么就剩个脑袋飘着
Why are you just a floating head?
要不你给我们说说  达伦
Maybe you could walk us through this, Darren.
你把达伦扔在量子领域等死
You left Darren to die in the Quantum Realm.
但是征服者发现了我
But the Conqueror found me.
令我重生
Rebuilt me.
将成我打造了终极武器
Made me the ultimate weapon.
一个机械化生命体  专为...
A mechanized organism designed only for...
魔多客
M.O.D.O.K.?
我懂了  是首字母缩写
I get it. It's an acronym.
是首字母缩写
It's an acronym.
机械化生命体  专为杀戮
Mechanized organism designed only for killing.
那你应该叫魔多法克
Actually, that's M.O.D.O.F.K.
-你一定以为再也见不到我了   -我才发现你的腿好像小宝宝的腿
-I bet you thought you'd seen the last of me.   -Just now noticing the baby legs.
才不像小宝宝
They're not baby legs.
你好像婴儿背带
A little bit like a Björn.
你以为自己很聪明是吧
You think you're so smart.
斯科特·朗  你夺走了我的一切
Scott Lang, the man who took everything from me.
偷走了我的人生
Who stole my whole life.
但我做到了
But I did it.
我把你们抓来了
I got you here.
我发现了你的信号  凯茜
I found your signal, Cassie.
多亏了你  不然我不会成功的
Thanks for that, by the way. Couldn't have done it without you.
你眼前的我得到了解放
You're looking at a man set free.
我在这里创造的成果多到你们无法想象
I've created so much more here than you could possibly imagine.
全都是为了他
All for him.
被困在量子领域的不止我一个人
I wasn't the only one stranded in the Quantum Realm.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
他说他是一个旅行者
He said he was a traveler.
一名科学家  飞船偏航坠落至此
A scientist who crashed off course.
他有一艘飞船...
He had a ship...
是我从未见识过的科技
beyond anything I had ever seen.
一艘能穿梭多元宇宙的飞船
A ship that could travel the Multiverse.
多元宇宙
The Multiverse?
你是说多维度吗
As in alternate dimensions?
平行现实
Parallel realities?
我刚开始也不相信
I didn't believe it at first.
但确实是真的
But it's real.
就跟我们的推论一样
Just like we theorized.
这艘船能送我们回去吗
Can this take us home?
它能送你去任何地方
It can take you anywhere.
我从没见过像他那般的人
I'd never met anyone like him.
他感觉好像...
He felt so...
十分迷惘
lost.
可能我们都是如此
I guess we both were.
但我们找到了出去的方法
But we had a way out.
我们试了各种方法...
We tried everything...
给飞船的动力核心充能
to recharge his ship's energy core.
都没能成功
Nothing worked.
但我独自一人这么多年
But after so many years alone,
能有个朋友也不错了
it was nice to have a friend.
我骗了霍普
I lied to Hope.
我告诉她我会回家的
I told her I was coming home.
我仿佛能看到她站在门口
I can see her by the door.
等着我回家
Waiting for me.
我离开前做的最后一件事...
That's the last thing I did...
竟是对她撒谎
was lie to her.
我总以为还有很多时间
I just thought I'd have more time.
我可以满足你
I can give that to you.
给你时间
Time.
时间并不是你想的那样
It's not what you think it is.
时间是个牢笼
It's a cage.
它会用尽一切方法...
And it does everything it can...
击垮你
to break you.
直到你挣脱出来才发现...
It's not until you free yourself from it that you see...
时间在本质上...
just how small...
是多么渺小
it always was.
我们一定能离开这里
We're going to get out of here.
她一打开门...
She's gonna open the door...
就会发现你在门口
and you'll be there.
我保证
I promise.
-继续干活吧   -好
-Let's get to work.   -Okay.
我们花了很长时间研究  但我们成功了
It took ages, but we did it.
飞船能够重新运作了
We brought it back to life.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
飞船是用神经驱动的
His ship was neurokinetic.
与他的思维连结
Connected to his thoughts.
当我触摸到飞船时...
When I touched it...
我窥见了他的内心
I saw his mind.
我感受到了...
I felt...
他所做的一切
what he had done.
这么多世界...
Entire worlds...
这么多条时间线...
entire timelines.
全部毁于一旦  就好像从未存在过
Gone, like they never even existed.
珍妮特
Janet?
我们可以走了
We can leave.
现在就走
Right now.
康是谁
Who is Kang?
是我要充当的角色
Who I need to be.
他不是意外坠落至此
He didn't crash here.
他是被流放到这儿的
He was exiled here.
独立于时间空间之外
Outside space and time.
只有这里...
The only place...
可以困住他
that could hold him.
被流放
Exiled?
被谁流放
By who?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他们毁了他的飞船
But they sabotaged his ship.
把他困在了这里
And trapped him here.
结果因为我...
And because of me...
他就要逃脱了
he was getting out.
珍妮特
Janet?
离我远点
Stay away.
你救过我
You saved my life.
我向你保证过
I made a promise.
让我送你回家吧
Just let me take you home.
然后呢
And then?
你打算干什么
What are you going to do?
取胜
Win.
我说过时间不是你想的那样
Itold you time isn't what you think.
我可以摆布时间...
I can make it...
让你从未离开过你的女儿
so you never left her.
霍普打开门就会发现...
Hope is going to open the door...
你在门外
and you'll be there.
那你出去以后...
And how many worlds will die...
又会有多少个世界被毁灭
if you get out?
至少你的不会
Not yours.
她永远不会知道
She'll never know.
你不想再见到你的女儿吗
Don't you want to see your daughter again?
我不能放你走
I can't let you leave.
你凭什么觉得你能拦住我
Why do you think you can stop me?
把它给我  珍妮特
Give it to me, Janet.
快点给我
Give it to me!
我打不过他  他太强大了
I couldn't beat him. He was too powerful.
你做了什么
What did you do?
对不起  霍普
I'm sorry, Hope.
不要
No!
我炸了动力核心
I blew up his core.
把他跟时间彻底隔绝
Cut him off from time.
也意味着我们永远困在这里了
And trapped us both down here forever.
但我还是给了他足够的力量
But I gave him back enough.
现在他取回了他的战衣...
Now that he had his suit back...
变回了他以前一直扮演的角色
he became what he always was.
征服者
A conqueror.
他掌握的科技和武器
He's got weapons and technology...
就算再过几百年我们也望尘莫及
centuries beyond anything we can dream of.
他将他的监狱变成了他的帝国
He took his prison and made it his empire.
我花了很长时间...
I spent years...
与他抗衡  四处躲藏  逃离他的追捕
fighting him, running from him, hiding from him.
直到后来你们把我救出去
And then you saved me.
带我回家
You brought me home.
但我不配
But I didn't deserve it.
我放出了一个猛兽  任由他在这里横行肆虐...
I unleashed a monster on this place...
却自己逃跑了
and ran away.
珍妮特  谁都没想到会这样
Janet, you couldn't have known.
对不起  我一直闭口不谈
I'm sorry I never told you.
我只是想忘却这里的一切
I just wanted to forget.
我只想重新做回你的妈妈
I just wanted to be your mom again.
抱歉  让你独自承受这么多
I'm so sorry you had to go through all of that alone.
但现在有我们陪着你了
But you are not alone now.
我们会一起阻止他
We'll stop him together.
他想要夺回核心
He's after the core.
但他需要皮姆粒子才能靠近核心
But he needs Pym Particles to reach it.
如果他抓住了斯科特和凯茜  那他就有皮姆粒子了
And if he's got Scott and Cassie, he's got Pym Particles.
-还抢先了一步   -没错
-And a head start.   -Exactly.
-得赶紧行动了   -霍普
-We gotta get out of here.   -Hope.
绝对不能让他出去
He cannot get out.
你很有意思...
You're an interesting man...
斯科特·朗
Scott Lang.
我不知道你是谁...
I don't know who you are...
但你犯了个大错
but you've made a big mistake.
懂吗
Okay?
我可是复仇者
I'm an Avenger.
我已经呼叫了其他复仇者...
I've called the other Avengers...
你是复仇者
You're an Avenger?
我之前杀过你吗
Have I killed you before?
什么
What?
过去太久我有点记不清了
They all blur together after a while.
你不是那个拿锤子的吧
You're not the one with the hammer?
不是  那是索尔
No, that's Thor.
经常有人分不清我们  我俩体型太像  你到底是谁
We get confused a lot. Similar body types. Who are you?
只是一个...
Just a man...
失去了很多时间的人
who's lost a lot of time.
就像你一样
Like you.
但我们可以联手找回来
But we can help each other with that.
魔多客说你很擅长偷东西
M.O.D.O.K. tells me you're a good thief.
对  他偷了我的东西
Yeah, he stole something from me.
我在的时候没你说话的份
Do not speak when I am in the room.
说真的  珍妮特比你有用多了
Gotta say, Janet was a lot more helpful.
你也认识珍妮特
You know Janet too?
这里的人是不是都认识珍妮特
Does everyone down here know Janet?
她没有提起过我么
She didn't tell you about me?
倒也合理
I guess that's not a surprise.
珍妮特从我这里偷走了一样东西
Janet stole something from me.
我离开这里的船票
My ticket out of here.
只有你能把它偷回来
You are the only one who can steal it back
我为什么要帮你
And why would I do that?
因为你们想离开这里
Because you want to get out of here.
而我必须要离开这里
And I need to get out of here.
因为我知道结局
Because I know how it ends.
什么结局
How what ends?
一切的结局
All of it.
我不存在于任何一条时间线内
I don't live in a straight line.
当你掌控了时间...
And with time...
你很难...
it's hard...
不直接跳到结局
not to skip to the end.
所以  如果你们想阻止接下来要发生的一切...
So, if you want to stop what's coming...
相信我...
and trust me...
你们一定会想要阻止的...
you do...
我是你们唯一的机会
I am the only shot you have.
接下来会发生什么
What's coming?
我
Me.
很多个我
A lot of me.
他们把我流放到这里
They exiled me, down here.
因为他们害怕我
They're afraid of me.
但只有我能让你们回去
But I'm the man who can get you home.
所以
So,
就这么说定了么
do we have a deal?
不  没说定
No, I don't think we do.
爸爸
Dad!
我帮你省点事
Let me make this easy for you.
你帮我拿来我需要的东西...
You will bring me what I need...
不然我就当着你的面杀了你女儿
or I will kill your daughter in front of you...
然后让你重温那一刻...
then make you relive that moment...
一遍又一遍  无休无止...
over and over again in time, endlessly...
直到你求我杀了你
until you beg me to kill you.
你听懂了吗
Do we understand?
拜托不要这样做
Don't do this.
我喜欢听得懂我说话的人
I'm a man who likes to be understood.
爸爸
Dad.
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
不  不要  听着  我们好好谈谈
No! No! Look, we can talk about this.
别帮他
Don't do it!
不做的话你会后悔的
You really should do it.
拜托
Please.
那是我的女儿  拜托了
That's my daughter, please.
你是想要她活呢  还是想要她死
Do you want her to live, or do you want her to die?
拜托了
Please!
你觉得我在吓唬你吗
You think I'm lying?
我看起来像在和你开玩笑吗
Do I look like a liar to you?
住手
Stop!
-爸爸   -我去  我去
-Dad!   -I'll do it. I'll do it.
我会去的  拜托放了她
I'll do it. Just let her go.
住手  快点住手
Let her go. Let her go!
你并不是万能的
You're out of your league.
蚁人
Ant-Man.
你应该为我还需要你感到幸运
Just be glad I need you.
不准再伤害她
Don't touch her again.
那就把我想要的东西带来
Then give me what I need.
在哪里
Where is it?
那是什么东西
What is that?
是一个万能引擎核心
It was a multiversal engine core.
一个可以带你到任何时空的能量源
A power source that can take you anywhere in space and time.
珍妮特炸了它
Then Janet blew it up.
引擎核心在那里面吗
It's in that?
那个就是引擎核心
It is that.
我们需要进到引擎核心里去
And we have to get to the center.
真是个好消息
That's good to know.
你必须缩小身体  穿过风暴中心
You'll have to shrink down and pass through the eye of the storm.
你进去了之后  找到核心...
Once you're inside, find the core...
缩小它的尺寸
and size it back down.
这个核心长什么样
What does it look like?
要我取偷东西的话  我需要知道我在偷什么
When I steal something, I usually know what I'm stealing.
你看到就知道了
You'll know it when you see it.
快去快回
Get in and out as fast as you can.
你在里面呆的时间越久  思想就会越混乱
The longer you're in there, the more your mind will come undone.
最好快点
Better hurry.
爸爸
Dad!
对不起
I'm sorry.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
不怪你
No.
我搞砸了
I messed up.
凯茜
Cassie.
我搞砸了我的整个人生
My whole life happened because I messed up.
唯一没有搞砸的事情就是有了你
The only thing I didn't mess up is you.
爸爸
Dad!
没关系
It's okay.
没事的
我爱你  小花生
I love you, Peanut.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我进来了
Okay. I'm in.
达伦  你听得见吗
Darren, can you hear me?
达伦
Darren?
魔多客  你听得见吗
M.O.D.O.K., can you hear me?
干什么
What?
-我进来了   -好的
-I'm in.   -Okay.
我现在要干什么  计划是什么
Okay, so what do I do? What's the plan?
别死
Don't die?
谢谢你  你真是帮了大忙了  魔多客
Thanks. Big help, M.O.D.O.K.
你看见核心了吗
Do you see it?
我看到了
Yeah. I see it.
我正在靠近它
I'm heading in.
什么鬼
What the hell?
我告诉过你的  斯科特  进入核心只是第一步
I told you, Scott. Getting in was just the beginning.
你没说过这个情况
You never said that.
为什么有另一个我
Why am I looking at another me?
我才不是另一个  你才是另一个
I'm not another me. You're another me.
你刚刚才冒出来...
You just came out...
为什么这里有另一个我
Why am I looking at another me?
你看到的是另一种可能性的你自己
You're looking at the possibility of another you.
你在概率风暴中
You're in a Probability Storm.
那是什么意思
What does any of that mean?
-你不知道吗   -我怎么会知道
-You don't know?   -Why would I know?
是你把我弄到这里来的
Because you got me in here.
所以我才是真的  对吧
So, I am the real one, huh?
不  我没说过这话
No. I didn't say that.
-什么鬼   -什么鬼
-What the hell?   -What the hell?
-停  停  停   -什么鬼
-Wait. Wait, wait.   -What the hell?
什么鬼
What the hell?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这里是概率风暴
It's a Probability Storm.
所有你可能做的选择都同时存在
Every choice you could make, existing all at once.
他说什么  他在说什么
What is he saying? What's he saying?
-他怎么说   -你在薛定谔的盒子里
-What's he saying?   -You're inside Schrödinger's box.
你是薛定谔的猫
And you're the cat.
-这说不通   -哦  我懂了
-That doesn't make sense.   -Oh, I get it.
都不准动  听到没  都不准动
Nobody move! All right? Nobody move!
为什么要听你的  你又不是真的
Why should we listen to you? You're not even the real one.
-什么鬼   -我是真的吗
-What the hell?   -Am I real?
-我是真的吗   -我是真的吗
-Am I real?   -Am I real?
-我就是真的   -什么鬼
-I am the real one!   -What the hell?
什么鬼  我就是真的
What the hell. I'm the real one.
伙计们  冷静一点
Guys. Hey, relax.
放轻松  深呼吸
Take it easy. Breathe.
我们能一起解决的
We'll figure this out. Together.
你是谁啊
Who are you?
你为什么穿成这样
Why are you dressed like that?
因为我在冰淇淋店工作啊
Because I work at Baskin-Robbins.
这是我的工作服
This is my uniform.
就是普通的衣服
These are normal clothes.
为什么你们穿成这样
Why are you dressed like that?
-你有冰淇淋吗   -够了
-Do you have ice cream?   -Enough!
冲啊
Let's do this!
完蛋了  我们都得死
Oh, we're all gonna die.
等等
Wait.
等一下
Wait. Wait!
不  不
No! No!
不  等一下  不
No! Wait! No!
我收到斯科特的讯息了
I've got a read on Scott.
别挡道
Out of the way!
-妈妈  这是什么情况   -你在干嘛
-Mom! What is this?   -What are you doing?
别管她们  她们只是可能性
Don't look at them. They're just possibilities.
她们不是你
They're not you.
斯科特  你在哪
Scott, where are you?
我为什么在这里
Why am I here?
别担心  这次一定行
Don't worry. It'll work this time.
你干嘛...等一下  快住手
What are you... Wait, wait, no, no. Stop.
-别这样  不   -我可以的  伙计们
-Stop! No!   -I got this, guys.
我可以的  我可以的
I got this! I got it!
斯科特  你在哪
Scott, where are you?
斯科特
Scott!
你在哪里  斯科特
Where are you, Scott?
-我喘不过气了   -嗷  那是我的脖子
-I can't breathe.   -Ow, that's my neck.
不准踢我
Stop kicking me!
-我的背   -我们都得死
-My back!   -We're all gonna die!
爸爸
Dad.
快回来
Come back.
爸爸...
Dad...
你如果听得到
if you can hear me...
快回来  一定要回来
come back. Just come back.
-不要放弃   -加油
-Don't give up.   -Come on.
-爸爸  这次也一定要回来   -加油
-Dad, just come back one more time.   -Come on.
-她需要我们   -拜托了
-She needs us.   -Please.
-对的  加油   -快回来
-Yes, come on.   -Come back.
她需要我们  我们一起
She needs us. Let's do it together.
-把他弄上来   -抓住他  快抓住他
-Get him up! Get him up!   -Grab him! Grab him!
走
Let's go.
-加把劲  把他抬起来   -好
-Come on, lift him!   -Yes!
-我抓住你了  我抓住你了  走你   -加油  就是这样
-I got ya, I got ya! Go.   -Come on. That's it.
-加把劲   -给他助力一下
-Come on!   -Give him a boost! Give him a boost!
加把劲  我们都是为了凯茜  伙计们加把劲
Come on, we're doing it for Cassie! Fellas, let's go!
所有人一起
Everyone together!
你做了什么
What are you doing?
你怎么做到的
How are you able to do that?
我告诉你为什么
I'll tell you how.
我们的目标是一致的
We all want the same thing.
我们都是为了凯茜
And I'm coming, Cassie.
去找她吧  伙计
Go get her, pal.
所有人  坚持住
Everyone, let's go!
加油
Come on!
加油  再近一点
Come on, closer.
把他抬高一点
Get him higher!
坚持住  伙计们
Hang on, guys, hang on.
小心点  别晃  别晃
Careful. Steady, steady.
稳一点  就是这样
Steady. That's it.
坚持住
Let's go.
什么
What?
-哦  不   -怎么样  成功了吗
-Oh no.   -What happened? Did it work?
抱歉  兄弟
Sorry, buddy!
-不   -不
-No, no, no.   -No, no, no.
霍普  你是真的吗
Hope, are you real?
我是真的
I'm real.
去拿核心吧
Then let's do this.
准备好了吗
You ready?
我准备好了
Ready.
快点
Come on.
我们得把这个东西弄走
We gotta get that thing out of here.
不不不  等一下  凯茜被抓了
No, no, no. Wait. He's got Cassie.
-什么   -斯科特
-What?   -Scott.
-珍妮特   -把核心给我
-Janet.   -Give that to me.
-我们得马上离开   -不行
-We have to go now.   -No.
他抓了凯茜
He's got Cassie.
我们会救她的  我保证我们会救她...
We will save her. I promise you we will save her...
但是你不能把核心给他
but you cannot give that to him.
换我就不会相信她
I wouldn't trust her.
珍妮特总是...
Janet has a way of...
三心二意的
changing her mind.
你好啊  小糖豆
Hello, Jellybean.
所以...
So...
你准备怎么做  斯科特
what's it gonna be, Scott?
瞧瞧谁来了
Well, well.
这不是我以前的老师吗
If it isn't my old mentor.
嗨  汉克
Hi, Hank.
达伦
Darren?
-没想到还能再见你的徒弟吧   -我的天呐  达伦
-Didn't expect to see your protégé again after all...   -Holy shit, Darren.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
我是终极武器
I'm the ultimate weapon!
要我亲自出手吗
Do I need to take it?
我女儿呢
Where is my daughter?
斯科特
Scott.
别给他
Don't.
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
没有你她也会过得很好
She'll be fine without you.
永别了  汉克
So long, Hank.
亨利
Henry.
你把我留在这里等死
You left me right here to die.
把他们留在这里  看看会发生什么
Let's see how they do.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
上次我们还没机会好好谈谈
We didn't really get a chance to talk about it last time.
但是我一直很好奇
But I always wondered.
当你触碰到我的思想...
When you touched my mind...
你看到了什么
what did you see?
一个怪物...
A monster...
自诩为神
who thinks he's a god.
当你能像我一样看清时间的本质...
When you can see time the way I do...
你就不会选择视而不见了
you don't get to close your eyes.
你以为众人皆醉你独醒吗
And you're the only one who sees?
我是唯一一个能看到时间崩坏的人
I am the only one that can see it's broken.
那是谁打破了时间
And who broke it?
是我
I did.
每一个版本的我
Every version of me.
我的变体
My variants.
穿越多元宇宙
Throughout the Multiverse.
就像孩童一样玩弄时间
Playing with time, like children.
但是我看到了结局
But I saw how it ends.
我看到混乱...
I saw their chaos...
在现实中蔓延
spreading across realities.
宇宙碰撞
Universes colliding.
无尽的入侵
Endless incursions.
我看到了多元宇宙
I saw the Multiverse.
它奄奄一息
And it was dying.
都是因为那些变体
All because of them.
所以  我控制了他们
So, I took control.
你的意思是你发动了战争
You mean you started a war.
现在你想要消灭所有对你有威胁的宇宙
And now you wanna wipe away any universe that's a threat to you.
只有怪物才这么做
That's what monsters do.
这正是征服者要做的
That's what conquerors do.
摧毁崩坏的世界
They burn the broken world.
然后创造一个新的世界
And they make a new one.
你不在乎拯救万事万物
You don't care about saving anything or anyone.
你只是想要复仇  因为他们打败了你
You only want revenge because they beat you.
-因为你输了   -我不止输了
-Because you lost.   -I have lost.
你都无法想象我输掉了什么
You have no idea what I have lost.
他们对我的所作所为...
And I will burn them out of time...
我会让他们血债血偿
for what they've done to me.
你会抹去整条的时间线
You'll be wiping out entire timelines.
杀害数万亿人
Murdering trillions of people.
这和我没关系  珍妮特
I wish that mattered, Janet.
哦  我的天  我在做什么
Oh, God. What am I doing?
什么
What?
汉克
Hank!
这些是你的蚂蚁吗
Are these your ants?
蚂蚁农场的
From the ant farm?
是的  斯科特  这些是我的蚂蚁
Yes, Scott, they're my ants.
你是怎么在这儿找到它们的
How did you find them down here?
自从坠落之后  我一直收到奇怪的信号
I've been picking up strange signals ever since we crashed.
一开始我以为是机器故障
First I thought maybe it was a malfunction.
某种干扰
Some kind of interference.
这是什么声音
What is that?
但不是的
But it wasn't.
是蚂蚁
It was the ants.
它们一直想联系上我
They were reaching out the whole time.
显然  它们经历了某种时间膨胀
Apparently, they passed through some sort of time dilation.
它们在一天之内进化了几千年...
They've lived thousands of years in a single day...
扩展它们的知识  它们的科学...
expanding their knowledge, their science...
变得比我想象的还要先进
becoming more advanced than I could have ever thought.
我没有找到它们
I didn't find them.
是它们找到了我
They found me.
我告诉过你  它们很聪明
I told you they were smart.
它们已经建立起了技术官僚二级文明
They've already built something of a technocratic Class-Two civilization.
我想说  虽然社会主义是一个有争议的词...
I mean, I know socialism is a charged word...
-但我们可以从中学到很多...   -爸爸
-but we could learn a lot from these...   -Dad.
是的  它们是我的蚂蚁
Yeah, they're my ants.
-以及  蚂蚁永不放弃   -我不在乎这个男的是谁
-And ants don't give up.   -I don't care who this guy is.
我也不在乎他有多大本事  我只要救出凯茜
I don't care what he can do. I'm getting Cassie.
那么我们怎样才能提高打败康的胜算呢
So, how do we even the odds against Kang?
我们有些想法
We've got some ideas.
你怎么想的
What are you thinking?
这个嘛  就像某位大作家说的那样...
Well, as a great writer once said...
"我们总有成长的空间"
"There's always room to grow."
你看了我的书
You read my book?
每句鬼话都看了
Every goddamn word.
走吧  该干正事了
Come on. Let's go to work.
嘿  对不起
Hey! I'm sorry.
刚刚可能有点吓人
That was probably terrifying.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我来救你
I'm rescuing you.
怎么救
How?
好问题
That's a good question.
这东西可以用钥匙开吗  或者刷卡
Does this thing have like a key? Or a card?
比如说房卡
Like a room key?
你知道吗  就像...
Do you know, like a...
糟糕
Shit!
跳起来  踢一脚
Jump and tap.
詹托拉
Jentorra.
很抱歉连累你们的人受伤了
I'm sorry I got your people hurt.
我能做些什么吗
How can I help?
哇
Wow.
回敬他们
Let's hurt 'em back.
你帅的要命
Damn, you're cool.
你有计划了吗
Do you have a plan?
其实救你就是我的计划
Freeing you was basically my plan.
你有计划么
Do you have a plan?
我们得让还能战斗的人们知道发生了什么
We need to get a message out to anyone who can still fight.
然后把我的人从下面的监狱里放出来...
Then free our people from the detention cells below...
然后从内部发起反攻
and launch a counteroffensive from within.
计划通  所以我们怎么才能通知其他人
Yeah, you have a plan. So, how do we get a message out?
跟我来
Follow me.
好的
Okay. Great.
珍妮特  我在这里创建了自己的帝国
I built an empire down here, Janet.
我也会带着他们一起离开
And I'm taking it with me.
那时你就应该放我离开的
You really should've let me out when you had the chance.
历史并非谱写而成
History is not written.
而是以血肉铸造
It is forged.
今天  我们将离开此处
Today, we ascend.
以我铸造起的堡垒  向那些驱逐我的人复仇
From this fortress, I will take my revenge on those who banished me.
今天我们征服永恒
Today we conquer eternity.
康王朝将...
And the dynasty of Kang shall...
听得到么  这行得通么
Hello? Is this working?
凯茜
Cassie?
我不知道有没有连上
I can't tell if this is working.
好了 应该是连上了
Okay. I think we're on.
我来拖住追兵 你来通知所有人
I'll hold them off. Get the message out.
我以为是你来
I thought you were getting the message out.
快点
Now!
我们现在在里面  突破了塔楼
We're inside. We breached the tower.
我和詹托拉在一起
And I'm with Jentorra.
他并不是无坚不摧的
He's not invincible.
我知道大家可能觉得...
I know it might feel like...
已经太迟了...
it's too late...
觉得我们只能坐以待毙
like all we do is just lose.
但我所失去的家人...
But the family I've lost...
教会了我永不轻易放弃
taught me to keep fighting.
如果他们现在在这里 也会战斗到底的
And if they were here, they would too.
我们需要保护所有小人物
We need to look out for the little guy.
这是我父亲教会我的
My dad taught me that.
因为当有人需要帮助时...
'Cause when people needed help...
他总会挺身而出
he didn't look the other way.
而我们也是如此
And neither do we.
我们得走了
We need to move!
请大家都来塔楼  和我们一起反击吧
Come to the tower! Fight back!
我知道你们一直都在伺机而动  现在反击的时候到了
I know you've been waiting. Now is the time to strike.
他很清楚他无法打败我们所有人
He knows he can't take all of us.
来...
Come to the...
凯茜
Cassie.
我查到信号是从何处发出的了  妈妈肯定也在那里
I think I found the signal. Mom's gotta be there, too.
-我们走吧   -我来驾驶
-Let's go.   -I'll drive.
找到朗的女儿
Find Lang's daughter.
杀了她
Kill her.
快走  快走
Let's go. Let's go!
如果你想战斗就跟我走
If you want to fight, follow me!
到此为止了  凯茜
It's over, Cassie.
把其他人都放出来  快去
Free the others. Go!
他肯定猜到我们会来
He's gonna see us coming.
是  就是要他看见
Yeah. I'll make sure of it.
开始发射
Begin the launch.
你爸可不在这儿  凯茜...
Your dad's not here, Cassie...
但我想这对你来说并不稀奇
but I guess that's not a big surprise.
康
Kang!
你出尔反尔
We had a deal.
带走了我的女儿
You took my daughter!
好家伙
Holy shit.
这么大
That's big.
你骗了我
You lied to me!
君子一言  驷马难追
Our word is our bond.
无法遵守诺言  做人都不配
Without that, we're nothing!
弄死他
Bring him down.
遵命
Yes, sir.
继续  我来搞定他们
Keep going. I've got them.
来吧
Yeah, come on!
他们太多了
There's so many!
斯科特  我拖不住他们
Scott! I can't hold them!
他们来了
They came.
好样的  凯茜
Way to go, Cassie!
太好了
Yes!
我们走  冲啊
Come on! Let's go!
革命万岁
Revolution!
都毁灭吧
Burn it all down.
冲啊
Fight!
找掩护  都趴下
Cover! Get down!
桥的密码是多少
What is the bridge code?
我死都不会说的
I'll die first.
One-eight-one-four-seven.
该死
Damn!
我想你需要这个
You'll need this.
你好
Hi.
这是我们的家园
This is our home!
让我们把它夺回来
Let's take it back!
不要
No!
我有洞了
I have holes.
I have holes!
我不知道他还能这样
I didn't know he could do that.
康
Kang!
她在哪里
Where is she?
现在就发射
Launch now!
这是什么
What is that?
他要离开了
He's getting out.
哦不  不能让他离开
Oh, no, he's not.
把他从环上引开
Keep him away from the rings.
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  我来了
Dad, I'm coming!
爸爸
Dad!
现在无处可逃了吧
Nowhere left to run.
拜托一定要成功
Please let this work.
嘿  你要去哪
Hey, where do you think you're going?
赶紧的
Let's go.
-你以为这样就完事了  赶紧杀了我   -达伦  别...
-You think this is over? Come on! Let's go.   -Darren, just stop...
老是这样
trying to be whatever this is.
我不知道该怎样
I don't know what to be.
告诉我该怎样
Tell me what to be.
我不知道  反正别当混蛋
I don't know. Just don't be a dick.
太迟了
It's too late.
看看我
Look at me.
我已经是个彻头彻尾的混蛋了
I'm such a dick.
醒悟永远都不迟
It's never too late to stop being a dick.
我们得阻止他
We've gotta stop him.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
准备好了么
Ready?
可能没有
Probably not.
一  二  三  就现在
One, two, three. Now!
爸爸
Dad!
凯茜
Cassie?
你变大了
You're huge.
我变大了
I'm huge.
我爱你  我的小花生
I love you, Peanut.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
我感觉在抱哥斯拉
I feel like I'm hugging Godzilla.
我知道  感觉很酷是吧
I know. It feels so cool.
是的
I know, right?
-我好饿   -是的
-I'm so hungry.   -Yeah,
-是会这样   -我感觉什么都能吃掉
-that happens.   -I could eat everything.
所有东西  我懂
Everything. I know.
-但我特别想吃酸橙   -是吧
-But I really want like a lime.   -Right?
-柑橘橙子之类的  我知道   -没错
-Citrus. It's weird. I know.   -Citrus.
是...
It's...
占领高塔
Take the tower!
一切都结束了
It's over.
你还是不明白
You still can't see it.
永远不会结束
It's never over.
-我们现在得走了   -不
-We have to go, right now.   -No.
-快点   -不
-Come on.   -No!
我知道  我知道  但我们得走了
I know, I know, but we have to go.
-不   -快
-No!   -Come on.
你个混...
You son of a...
-哦天呐   -斯科特
-Oh, God.   -Scott.
来
Come on.
你以为我没经历过这些么
You think this is new to me?
你知道我平定过多少叛乱吗
Do you know how many rebellions I have put down?
不不不
No, no, no.
你知道我征服过多少个世界吗
How many worlds I've conquered?
杀过多少复仇者么
How many Avengers I've killed?
你以为就凭你  能打败我么
And you think you can beat me?
我可是康
I am Kang!
你...
You...
就凭你个和蚂蚁说话的
You talk to ants.
我的名字是达伦...
My name is Darren...
我不是混蛋
and I am not a dick!
抱歉我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
蚂蚁太多了
Lotta ants.
哦  这是你干的啊
Oh, is this you?
你说的对  凯茜
You were right about me, Cassie.
达伦
Darren.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
好像不太好
Probably not.
-达伦   -你好  霍普
-Darren?   -Hi, Hope.
你剪头了
You changed your hair.
你怎么变成这样了
What the hell happened?
嗯  不...
Yeah. No...
说来话长  我待会儿再跟你说
It's a whole thing. I'll tell you later.
是...
That was...
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
谢谢你  斯科特
Thanks, Scott.
你对我来说就像兄弟一样
You always were a brother to me.
我是吗
I was?
我是
I was.
至少我是身为...
And at least I died...
复仇者联盟一员而死的
an Avenger.
是
Yeah.
-你说的对   -嗯  你入伙了
-You did.   -Yeah. You're in.
今天发生了太多
A lot has happened today.
-亨利   -珍妮特
-Henry?   -Janet?
-妈妈你在哪里   -我在塔中
Mom, where are you?   -I'm in the tower.
我可以为我们争取到一次回去的机会
I think I can give us one shot back.
但没有太多时间
But we don't have much time.
如果我们想回家...
If we wanna go home...
必须现在就走
we have to go now.
我们来善后
We'll finish this.
谢谢你
Thank you.
快来  我们走
Come on! Let's go!
好了  祝你们好运
All right. Good luck.
祝你们好运  走吧
Good luck. Come on.
谢谢你  兄弟
Thanks, buddy.
你做到了
You did it.
我们回家
Let's go home.
斯科特呢
Where's Scott?
他就在我后面来着
He was right behind me.
你不应该多管闲事
You should've looked the other way.
嗯好吧  我一直不擅长袖手旁观
Yeah, well, never been great at that.
我不会让你离开的
And you're not getting out.
我要你记住
I want you to remember.
你本可以回家的
You could've gone home.
你永远见不到你女儿了
You could've seen your daughter again.
你还以为自己能战胜我
But you thought you could win.
我不需要战胜你
I don't have to win.
我们可以一起输
We both just have to lose.
爸爸
Dad!
她在...她在...
Where... Where...
她在哪  她...
Where is she? Is she...
-她没事   -她在哪
-No, she's okay.   -Where is she?
她没事  她没事
She's okay. She's okay.
-斯科特  他们都没事  你做到了   -她安全吗
-Scott, they're all okay. They're all okay. You did it.   -She's safe?
你做到了
You did it.
-抱歉  抱歉  抱歉   -不不不
-Sorry. Sorry, sorry.   -No, no, no.
不  别放手  别放手
No, don't let go. Don't let go.
别放手
Don't let go.
永远别放手
Don't ever let go.
有我在
I got you.
你回来了
You came back.
我爱你  霍普
I love you, Hope.
我爱你  斯科特
I love you, Scott.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
回家真好
Home's good.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
我的生活确实过于离谱
My life doesn't make sense.
♪ Your dreams were your ticket out   你的梦想就是你的出路 ♪
对此我曾经问过自己很多问题
I used to ask myself a lot of questions about that.
"斯科特 你刚刚和家人一起拯救了量子领域..."
"Scott you just saved the Quantum Realm with your family...
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
"喝了身上没有洞的家伙的液体"
"and drank a guy without holes.
♪ To that same old place that you laughed about   回到老地方  让你捧腹大笑 ♪
"为什么你老是碰到这种事呢"
"Why does this kind of stuff keep happening to you?
"这也太离谱了"
That doesn't make any sense."
♪ Well the names have all changed since you hung around   自从你在我身边名字都变了 ♪
但你知道么
But you know what?
谁说生活一定要合理
Who said life has to make sense?
♪ But those dreams have remained   但那些梦想依然存在 ♪
♪ And they've turned around   他们已经转身离去 ♪
♪ Who'd have thought they'd lead ya   谁能想到他们会指引你 ♪
鲁宾
Rubin!
你就是那个虫子
You are the bug!
哦不对  你是另一个虫子
I was wrong. Yeah. You are the other bug.
♪ Back here where we need ya   回到我们需要你的地方 ♪
你就是那个虫子人
You're the bug man.
♪ Yeah we tease him a lot   我们经常戏谑他 ♪
你能变大虫还能变小虫
You get big and get small like a big bug!
♪ Cause we got him on the spot   因为我们让他无处可逃 ♪
你说的对  是我  我只是要杯咖啡  谢谢
You're right. That's me. Just a coffee, please.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
12美金
Twelve dollar.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
要12
Twelve!
我一直以为自己生命中的这一篇章已经结束...
I used to wonder if this chapter in my life was over...
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
但正如凯茜所说"总有你能帮助的人"
but as Cassie reminded me, "There's always someone you can help."
♪ We always could spot a friend   我们总能找到朋友 ♪
退休人员亲手为你做的蛋糕
Came out of cake making retirement for you.
生日快乐  凯茜
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
♪ And I smile when I think how you must have been   当我想起你过去的模样  我微微一笑 ♪
哇
Wow.
这是你自己做的么
You made this yourself?
-没错  我通常不亲自动手的   -我知道
-Yeah! I don't usually make the cakes.   -I know.
♪ And I know what a scene you were learning in   我知道你见多识广 ♪
这是我自1997年以来做的第一个蛋糕
This is the first one I've made since 1997.
你真是个艺术家
You're a real artist.
♪ Was there something that made you come back again  是不是有什么原因让你再次回来 ♪
这是段无比惊奇的经历
It's been a pretty wild ride.
前一秒你才刚被冰淇淋店解雇...
One day you're fired from Baskin-Robbins...
♪ And what could ever lead ya   究竟是什么指引着你 ♪
下一秒你就成功打败了时空穿梭之王
the next you're beating a time-traveling space king.
♪ Back here where we need ya   回到我们需要你的地方 ♪
我们打败了他  对吧
We did beat him, right?
所以事实就是这样
I mean, yeah, that's what happened.
♪ Yeah we tease him a lot   我们经常戏谑他 ♪
他想出来  但我们阻止了他
He was getting out and he didn't get out.
♪ Cause we got him on the spot   因为我们让他无处可逃 ♪
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
应该是吧
I think.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
但他也说很糟糕的事即将发生...
But he also said something bad was coming...
如果他不出来  所有人都会死
and that everyone would die if he didn't get out.
等等  那我是不是害死了所有人
Wait. So, did I just kill everyone?
所有人都会因为我而死吗
Is everyone gonna die because of me?
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
我...我都做了什么
Oh my... What did I do?
我都做了些什么
What did I do?
你知道么  应该没关系的
You know what? It's probably fine.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
正如我所说  生活从来不符合常理...
Like I said, life doesn't make any sense...
所以别问那么多问题了  斯科特
so maybe stop asking so many questions, Scott.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
别多想
Stop overthinking it.
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
惊喜
Surprise!
祝你生日快乐
Happy Birthday to you
♪ Welcome back   欢迎回来 ♪
今天不是我生日
It's not my birthday.
我知道  但我错过了好几个
I know. But I missed a few.
多好  所有人都在一起
This is good. We're all together.
没关系的
You're fine.
应该没事的
Everything's probably fine.
康已经死了  你成功了
Kang's gone. You did it.
不用再担心那个人了
Don't have to worry about that guy anymore.
谢谢
Thanks.
凯茜  假生日快乐
Happy fake birthday, Cassie.
导 演
佩顿·里德
编 剧
杰夫·洛维斯
制 片 人
斯蒂芬·布鲁萨德
凯文·费奇
监 制
路易斯·德·埃斯泼西托
维多利亚·阿隆索
监 制
凯文·德·拉·诺伊
联 合 制 片 人
劳拉·斯托尔茨
米奇·贝尔
摄 影 导 演
比尔·波普
美 工 设 计 师
威尔·泰
剪 辑
劳拉·詹宁斯
亚当·格斯特尔
根 据 漫 威 漫 画 改 编
服 装 设 计 师
萨米·谢尔顿·迪费
视 觉 特 效 总 监
杰西·詹姆斯·斯奇泽姆
视 觉 特 效 制 作 人
菲奥娜·坎贝尔·韦斯特盖特
音 乐
克里斯托弗·贝克
音 乐 总 监
戴夫·乔丹
选 角 导 演
萨拉·芬恩
保罗·路德
饰  斯科特·朗
翻译
野草
伊万杰琳·莉莉
饰  霍普·凡·戴恩
翻译
待我伸伸懒腰
乔纳森·梅杰斯
饰  康
翻译
醺醺
凯瑟琳·纽顿
饰  凯茜·朗
翻译
Kokko
大卫·达斯马齐连
饰  维布
翻译
阿嚏不是白打
凯蒂·奥布莱恩
饰  詹托拉
校对
Maryduan
威廉·杰克森·哈珀
饰  夸兹
时间轴
吴末
比尔·默瑞
饰  克里拉勋爵
时间轴&特效&压制
IJustFeelYou
米歇尔·菲佛
饰  珍妮特·凡·戴恩
寇瑞·斯托尔
饰  魔多客 / 达伦·克罗斯
迈克尔·道格拉斯
饰  汉克·皮姆
漫  威  影  业  出  品
VisionWanda字幕组  译制
凯 文·费 奇 制 片
蚁 人   与   黄 蜂 女
量  子  狂  潮
所以  被放逐的那个人死了
So, the exiled one is dead.
你确定他死了吗
You sure he's dead?
如果不确定  我不会联系你
If it wasn't true, I wouldn't call you.
你一定很懊恼  不是自己亲手杀了他
Must really eat you up, that you're not the one who killed him.
我们没能...
None of us...
杀了他
killed him.
他们却做到了
They did.
他们开始触及多元宇宙了
They're beginning to touch the Multiverse.
如果我们放任他们不管...
And if we let them...
他们将...
they will take...
夺走...
everything...
我们的一切
we've built.
所以别再浪费时间了
So let's stop wasting time.
要迟到了
We're late.
你叫了多少人
How many did you call?
所有人
All of us.
时间代表了一切
Time is everything.
维克多·坦姆利与他
令人震惊的时间奇迹
它塑造了我们的生活
It shapes our lives.
但或许 我们可以塑造...
But, perhaps, we can shape...
时间
it.
就是他
It's him.
什么  你不是说他很可怕么
What? You made him sound like this terrifying figure.
是的
He is.
康 将 会 回 归